U.S. Emergency Board No. 134 Records 5055
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board No. 134 Records
1961
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
U.S. Emergency Board
5055
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Transcripts of proceedings of the United States Emergency Board No. 134, under the Railway Labor Act. Proceedings concerned the New York Harbor Carriers' Committee and Lighter Captains Union, Local 996, International Longshoremen's Association.
5975950
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Leone W. Eckert, November 04, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
For many years Local 996, International Longshoremen's Association joined with the Nonoperating Railway Labor Organizations in negotiations and their agreement followed the national pattern. In 1957 the Local chose to negotiate directly with the carriers and signed an agreement on July 22.
On October 31, 1959 the Local notified the Carriers it would like to change the agreement, increasing the basic daily rate from $18.69 to $25. In addition, the Local would like a cost of living escalator clause, 20 cents per day added to the travel allowance, changes in the vacation agreement and an increased number of paid holidays, sick leave pay and severance pay.
The Carriers' countered with proposals to change the assignment rules, overtime provisions, and a reduction in paid holidays and no changes in the current wage rates.
Several negotiating meetings were held, but no progress in reaching an agreement was made, and on September 29, 1960 the Local broke off negotiations and set October 21, 1960 as the date to strike.
On January 12, 1961 the President created the Emergency Board of James T. O'Connell, Harold M. Gilden and David R. Douglass. The Board held hearings until February l6, 1961 and submitted its report on March 6, 1961.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of transcripts of proceedings of the United States Emergency Board No. 134, under the Railway Labor Act. Proceedings concerned the New York Harbor Carriers' Committee and Lighter Captains Union, Local 996, International Longshoremen's Association.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arbitration, Industrial; United States. Emergency Board No. 134.; New York Harbor Carriers Conference Committee; Lighter Captains Committee; International longshoremens Association. Local 996 (New York, N.Y.)
5975950
- Transcripts of proceedings. (Box 1)
  - Report to the President by the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    March 6, 1961
  - Report to the President by the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    January 26, 1961; pages 14-48
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    January 27, 1961; pages 49-131
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    January 30, 1961; pages 132-237
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    January 31, 1961; pages 238-358
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    February 2, 1961; pages 359-435
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    February 3, 1961; pages 436-490
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    February 13, 1961; pages 491-590
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    February 14, 1961; pages 591-710
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    February 15, 1961; pages 711-839
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    February 16, 1961; pages 840-959
  - Transcript of proceedings of the Emergency Board No. 134, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    February 17, 1961; pages 960-1114